# **Berat Ucar**

## Frontend Developer



≥ dev.beratucar@gmail.com

📞 +905537457033 🛭 💡 Ankara / Turkey

in LinkedIn 🕝 Github 🤘 Portfolio

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **Bootcamp Mobile Developer**

06/2023 - 07/2023 New York, United States

#### **Bootcamp** Frontend Developer

05/2022 - 10/2022 New York, United States

#### **Gazi University Civil Engineering**

2017 - 2022 | Ankara, Turkey

#### SKILLS

HTML (HTML5), CSS (CSS3), Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, JavaScript, SASS, React, Next.js, React Native, Redux.js, Redux Toolkit, Postman, RESTful APIs, Webpack, Unit Testing, NPM, Node.js, SDLC, Jira, Trello, Scrum, Agile Methods, CRM, Git, Github, Expo, Figma, AutoCAD, Microsoft Word, Microsoft Excel, PowerPoint

#### LANGUAGES

English (B2)

Turkish (Native)

#### \* REFERENCES

#### Doç. Dr. Özel Sebetci,

Founder, Associate Professor, University Lecturer, Author,

Gazi University, OSTİM Teknik University, Adnan Menderes University, Ankara Haci Bayram Veli University, BudunAI

osebetci@adu.edu.tr, +905323632446

Mike Clain, Account Manager, TalenTech Solutions mike.clain@talentechsolutions.com, +15852826326

Ali Aker, Account Manager, Rainpark Solutions ali.aker@rainparksolutions.com, +1(585)3161820

#### PROFILE

Frontend Developer with over 2 years of experience in Web Development, specializing in user experience Internet/Intranet applications. Proficient in Node.js, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, SASS, React.js, React Native, Redux.js, Next.js, and Git. Strong analytical and logical programming skills with a solid conceptual understanding. Demonstrates leadership, communication, teamwork, and problem-solving abilities to drive project success.

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

#### **Assistant Frontend Developer Instructor Bootcamp**

04/2023 - present | New York, United States

- Provided personalized guidance to aspiring frontend developers through one-on-one sessions, aiding them in preparing effective resumes and LinkedIn profiles to enhance their professional branding.
- Conducted individualized mock interviews, offering constructive feedback and tailored strategies to help students develop strong interview skills and boost their confidence.
- Collaborated with students in designing and executing frontend projects as part of the bootcamp curriculum, offering hands-on assistance and mentorship to ensure project success.
- Mentored students in refining their frontend coding skills, offering guidance on HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and popular frontend libraries/frameworks to foster their technical proficiency.
- Delivered comprehensive lessons on interview preparation techniques, including behavioral and technical aspects, resulting in increased student performance in real job interviews.
- Assisted students in preparing for market entry by offering insights into industry trends, resume optimization, and job market navigation, leading to improved placement rates.

#### Frontend Developer

### Budunai Bilişim ve Teknoloji San. Tic. Ltd. Şti. 🛭

09/2023 - 03/2024 | Ankara, Turkey

- Developed an artificial intelligence-enhanced job search platform similar to LinkedIn for Tubitak.
- Designed and implemented the company's website.
- Utilized Trello for project management.
- Executed the development of a mobile gaming application.

#### Mobile Developer Rent a Car Project

07/2023 - 09/2023 | United States, Internship

#### Front-End Developer **E-Commerce Project**

03/2023 - 06/2023 | United States, Internship

- Worked as part of the team on projects; receive regular guidance.
- Worked closely with team members to create consistent, reusable, and maintainable code; designed new software systems or updates to existing systems.
- Coordinated and participated in implementation, testing, and support.
- Ensured each build functions correctly on mobile, tablet, and desktop devices.

#### Front-End Developer Rent a Car Project

10/2022 - 03/2023 | United States, Internship

- Followed agile & scrum methods for the development of the product.
- Involving in building multiple UI components from design stage to production stage.
- Performed validation of completed sites including the debugging and testing of code.
- Designed a responsive website using Bootstrap grid system to layout contents that fit different devices including mobile, tablet and desktop.
- Cross-browser tested sites in Microsoft Edge, Safari, Firefox, Chrome and mobile browsers